RG 062:130, Town of Southbury
Connecticut State Library
Town of Southbury records
1788-1993
Connecticut State Library
Southbury (Conn.)
19 cubic feet
Administrative, land, election, justice of the peace, school, tax and military records for the town of Southbury.
RG062_130
Multiple
Historical Note
The town of Soutbbury was incorporated in May 1787 and was taken from Woodbury.
Scope and Content
Administrative, land, election, justice of the peace, school, tax and military records for the town of Southbury.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Elections -- Connecticut -- Southbury -- Statistics; Elections -- Connecticut -- Southbury -- Statistics; Schools -- Connecticut -- Southbury -- History -- Sources; Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Southbury -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- Southbury -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Southbury -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- Southbury -- Registers; Voting registers -- Connecticut -- Southbury; Soldiers -- Connecticut -- Southbury; Deeds -- Connecticut -- Southbury
Places:
Southbury (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence
Restrictions on Access
Some records in Accession T000993 are restricted due to mold. Specific records are identified in the container list. Please contact State Archives staff for assistance.
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Accession T000993, 1788-1921
  - Election reports, circa 1800-1900 (Box 1)
  - Justice Johnson's record of cases, 1791-1811 (Box 1)
  - First School Society Secretary's book, 1839-1909 (Box 1)
  - First School Society Treasurer's book, 1798-1856 (Box 1)
  - Assorted town records, 1803-1848 (Box 1)
    Restricted due to mold.
  - Selectmen's account book, 1788-1828 (Box 2)
  - Registers of Personal tax exemptions, 1917-1921 (Box 2)
  - Releases of tax liens, 1912-1915 (Box 2)
  - Tax abstracts, 1791, 1802-1860 (Box 3-4)
  - Individual tax lists, 1819-1908 (Box 5-18)
  - Deeds, 1854, 1856; 2 deeds (Box Item 19)
- Accession 2009-004, 1795-1993
  - Election records, 1900-1955
    - Applications for enrollment, 1947-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Applications for transfer of enrollment, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Electors of the Town of Southbury, circa 1942; 1 volume (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Covers 1787-1942.
    - List of persons applying to be made electors, 1900-1932; 1 volume (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Registrar's record of those who applied to be made electors, 1932-1940; 1 volume (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Voter list, 1942-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Voter lists
      - 1920, 1926-1941, 17 items (Box 2)
      - 1942, 1944-1955, 13 items (Box 3)
        There are two lists for 1942.
  - Tax records, 1873-1922
    - Personal tax enrollment and collection, 1917; 1 volume (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Rate book, 1873; 1 volume (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Rate book, 1877; 1 volume (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Rate book, 1914; 1 volume (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Rate book, 1922; 1 volume (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Military records, 1815-1832, 1936, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Errata: record of Connecticut men in the War of Rebellion, 1861-1865; Spanish-American War, Philippine Insurrection, China Relief Expedition: 1898-1904, 1936 January 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      A copy is available at
    - Roll of the 5th Company 13th Regiment Connecticut Militia, 1815-1832; 1 volume (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Vietnam War list of casualties by town, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous records, 1795-1982, undated
    - Headstone inscriptions, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - List of male residents with ages, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous historical data, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs of bridges, old and new town hall.
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1795, 1932, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Poison register, 1960-1963; 1 notebook (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - White Oak Cemetery fund ledger book, 1896-1955; 1 volume (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Town road system, 1959-1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)